GRAHAM NESSLER

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

graham@grahamnessler.com http://www.grahamnessler.com/ (215) 804-7381 (USA)

SUMMARY

I am a former history professor and <u>published author</u> turned software developer. I am most knowledgeable about React, React Native, Redux, jQuery, and JavaScript (ES6 and ES5), though I have worked with many other technologies, including newer tools such as Electron. I believe that the core purpose of technology is to improve people's lives, and I am continually pushing myself to learn new skills.

SKILLS

CORE TECHNICAL TOOLBOX: React.js, React Native, Redux, JavaScript/ES6, ExpressJS, jQuery, JSON, CSS/SASS, HTML5 Canvas, Ember, TDD, Websockets, HTML5, Firebase, Git/Github, Postgres and SQL, Webpack, Vim, Angular, Enzyme and Selenium, Mocha and Chai, Swift, Electron, Websockets

ADDITIONAL TECHNOLOGIES: Sketch, Atom, Sublime Text, Microsoft Office, Blackboard, Turnitin

OTHER SKILLS: Agile, Web accessibility/ARIA, Excellent writing skills, Proficient in Spanish, French, and English, Working knowledge of Brazilian Portuguese, Mentoring and leadership, Teaching and public speaking, Teamwork and group collaboration

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

Webdriver IO Add some clarifications to guide.md

Link

Debugpolitics.com Add hover color change for footer links and a readme

Link

Spell check for Atom text editor Revised readme for clarification

LINK

Promise It Won't Hurt (Nodeschool course) Some small changes for clarity (to instructions)

Link

PROJECTS

We The People

We The People is an application created in React Native that allows a user to track current Congressional bills and new laws. Using the <u>Sunlight Congress API</u>, the application brings in data on bills and laws including title, date introduced, date of last action, sponsor, current progress (in House Committee, passed by Senate, enacted...), and other data. This application is meant for concerned citizens (and non-citizens) to keep track of Congressional actions and to be better informed and empowered to take action on critical issues.

My core contributions: created the bill filter functionality; designed much of the React component architecture and built much of the UI from prototype; wrote all unit tests for client side code; did most of the routing and set up the drawer menu.

React Native, JavaScript, SVG, Express, Mocha, Chai

Flash Shopper

This is an independent solo project undertaken outside of the Turing School curriculum. It consists of a grocery list where users can enter in an item name, aisle, quantity, and a note. Users can also choose a category (such as "Bread") from a dropdown menu, which will then populate the aisle number (currently only for my local King Sooper's). The user can also sort items alphabetically and by aisle number and delete items.

React, Redux, Firebase, JavaScript, SASS/CSS, Webpack. See also my version in React Native.

(For other projects, please see my portfolio).

EXPERIENCE

Florida Atlantic University

Visiting Professor of History · Aug 2015 to May 2016, Aug 2015 to May 2016 · Boca Raton, FL

Taught courses in United States, Caribbean, Latin American, and global history to around 200 students

Bentley University

Post-Doctoral Fellow · Sep 2013 to Jul 2015 · Waltham, MA

- Completed book manuscript
- Taught an undergraduate course on dictatorships in modern Latin America

Texas A&M University--Commerce

Ad Interim Assistant Professor of History · Aug 2012 to May 2013, Aug 2012 to May 2013 · Commerce, TX

Taught courses in United States and Latin American history at both the graduate and undergraduate levels

EDUCATION

Turing School of Software and Design

Certificate in Front End Engineering 2017

University of Michigan

PhD History 2011

College of William and Mary

BA History 2005